Welcome.
欢迎。
In the last lecture we downloaded two new animations for climbing up the ledge and climbing
在上一节课中，我们下载了两个新的动画，用于爬上壁架和爬下壁架
down the ledge.
下台阶。
And in this lecture we'll look at how we can fix the root motion issue.
而在这一讲中，我们将看看如何解决根部运动的问题。
So first I'm going to go to the content, then I'm going to go to file and click new level
首先，我将进入内容，然后我将进入文件并点击新的级别
and I'm going to select this basic, click create.
我将选择这个基础，点击创建。
So later when we want to adjust the animation using Ctrl+Rick, it'll appear at the world
所以以后当我们想用Ctrl+Rick来调整动画时，它就会出现在世界的
origin.
原点。
Since the world origin in the third person map is a weird location, using a new empty
由于第三人称地图中的世界原点是一个奇怪的位置，在这里使用一个新的空的
map here should work the best.
地图应该是最有效的。
Then I'm going to go to file and click this save current level ads.
然后我将进入文件，点击这个保存当前级别的广告。
Then inside of this content folder I'm going to change this name to cr_nm_map.
然后在这个内容文件夹里面，我将把这个名字改为cr_nm_map。
And I'm going to click save.
然后我将点击保存。
So later if we need to adjust more animations I'm going to do it inside of this map.
所以以后如果我们需要调整更多的动画，我将在这张地图中进行。
And next thing I'm going to go back to this raw folder, then double click to open this
接下来我要回到这个原始文件夹，然后双击来打开这个
climbing to top.
攀升到顶部。
So I'm going to click this drop down and go to bake to control rick, select this cr_mannequin_body
所以我将点击这个下拉菜单，进入烘焙控制里克，选择这个cr_mannequin_body
and keep everything a default, click this bake to control rick.
并保持所有的东西都是默认的，点击这个烘烤来控制瑞克。
Then go back to my content browser and you can see this is what you should see.
然后回到我的内容浏览器，你可以看到这是你应该看到的。
We'll be inside of this animation mode.
我们将在这个动画模式里面。
This is the control rick for our mannequin.
这就是我们的人体模型的控制里克。
Note that there are two tracks and if I click play in here our mannequin is not moving.
请注意，这里有两条轨道，如果我点击这里的播放，我们的人体模型就不会移动。
So to fix this issue we'll need to delete the second track, so the track that does not have
所以为了解决这个问题，我们需要删除第二个轨道，也就是没有按键的那个轨道。
keys.
键。
So select this one, press delete.
所以选择这个，按删除。
And now if I click play again we can see the animation now.
现在，如果我再次点击播放，我们就可以看到动画了。
Alright I'm going to scroll back to the first frame and I'm going to click this drop down
好的，我将滚动到第一帧，并点击这里的下拉菜单
in here so we can see these are all the controls that we have.
所以我们可以看到这些是我们拥有的所有控制。
If this looks intimidating and you are thinking I'm not an animator there's no way that I'm
如果这看起来很吓人，你在想我不是一个动画师，我不可能做到这一点。
able to do this.
能够做到这一点。
Don't worry, we are not creating new animations completely from scratch in here.
不要担心，我们在这里不是完全从头开始创建新的动画。
We just need to remove and add some keys.
我们只是需要删除和添加一些键。
The only control that we are interested in is this root_control.
我们唯一感兴趣的控件是这个root_control。
So I'm going to select it and click this drop down and you can see we have control over
所以我要选择它并点击这个下拉菜单，你可以看到我们可以控制
its location, rotation, and scale.
它的位置、旋转和比例。
So I'm going to select this location x and hold down shift, select this rotation yaw.
所以我要选择这个位置x并按住shift，选择这个旋转yaw。
Once I have all of these rows selected I'm going to delete all of the keys in here.
一旦我选择了所有这些行，我将删除这里的所有键。
So select all of them, then press delete.
所以选择所有的，然后按删除。
Alright next thing, we just need to animate this root_control.
好了，下一件事，我们只需要把这个root_control做成动画。
So I'm going to click this icon here to add a new key to the current time.
所以我要点击这个图标，为当前时间添加一个新的键。
Then I'm going to forward a few frames.
然后我将向前推进几帧。
So the key here is as long as the root bone here follows the hips we should have a working
所以这里的关键是，只要这里的根骨跟着臀部走，我们就应该有一个有效的
root motion.
根部运动。
So about frame 44 I'm going to lift this root_control up to the hip.
所以大约在第44帧，我将把这个根部控制抬高到臀部。
Somewhere near here, then I'm going to click this button again to add a new key and I'm
在这里附近的某个地方，然后我将再次点击这个按钮来添加一个新的键，我将预览我们刚才的动作。
going to preview what we've just created.
预览我们刚刚创建的东西。
So you can see our root_control is moving.
所以你可以看到我们的root_control正在移动。
Let's go on.
让我们继续。
So I'm going to forward a few more frames to somewhere near here and I'm going to lift
所以我打算再往前走几格，到这里附近的某个地方，我打算把
this root_control a little bit to here, then move it to here.
这个root_control抬高一点到这里，然后把它移到这里。
Then click add key, then forward a few more frames.
然后点击添加键，再向前移动几帧。
So right about at frame 86 I'm going to move this root_control to here, lower it down to
因此，在第86帧的时候，我将把这个根控件移到这里，把它降低到
the height of the feet and move it to the center.
脚的高度，并把它移到中心。
So something like this and click add key.
所以像这样，然后点击添加键。
And that's pretty much it.
这就差不多了。
Now I'm going to preview this again.
现在，我将再次预览这个。
Alright, this should work just fine.
好了，这应该可以正常工作了。
So once we've made the adjustments we can create a new animation sequence.
所以一旦我们做了调整，我们就可以创建一个新的动画序列。
And to do that, first I'm going to click this climbing to top right mouse button click and
要做到这一点，首先我要点击这个攀升到顶部的鼠标右键，然后
here we have options to create an animation sequence.
这里我们有创建一个动画序列的选项。
I'm going to select this create linked animation sequence.
我将选择这个创建链接动画序列。
So by doing this, later if we need to make more adjustments, we can come back to this
所以通过这样做，以后如果我们需要做更多的调整，我们可以回到这个
sequencer, make the changes we need and sync the changes to this animation sequence.
序列器，做我们需要的修改，并将这些修改同步到这个动画序列。
Alright, I'm going to click it and here we need to select folder to save this animation
好的，我将点击它，在这里我们需要选择文件夹来保存这个动画序列。
sequence.
序列。
So I'm going to select this climb system, go inside of this animation, place it in this
所以我要选择这个攀登系统，进入这个动画的内部，把它放在这个
adjusted.
调整。
I'm going to rename this sequence to climb to top_cr linked and click OK.
我要把这个序列重命名为爬升到top_cr链接，然后点击确定。
And this is the window that you should see.
这就是你应该看到的窗口。
So we don't need to touch anything in here, just keep everything a default.
所以我们不需要碰这里的任何东西，只要保持所有东西都是默认的。
Then click this export to animation sequence.
然后点击这个导出到动画序列。
Alright here it says one asset created.
好了，这里显示创建了一个资产。
I'm going to go back to my content browser inside of this adjusted folder and you can
我将回到我的内容浏览器中，在这个调整后的文件夹中，你可以看到这是我们刚才的动画。
see this is the animation that we just created.
你可以看到这就是我们刚刚创建的动画。
Double click to open it.
双击来打开它。
Now you can see we have a working root motion for this animation.
现在你可以看到我们为这个动画创建了一个有效的根动作。
And if I go to the asset details now and click this enable root motion, this is something
如果我现在去看资产的细节，并点击这个启用根动作，这是一些
that you should see.
你应该看到。
So this indicates that we have a working root motion.
所以这表明我们有一个有效的根动作。
Alright I'm going to click save.
好了，我要点击保存。
Then close this window, right mouse button click this animation sequence and create a
然后关闭这个窗口，用鼠标右键点击这个动画序列并创建一个
new animation montage.
新的动画蒙太奇。
I'm going to call this one am_climb to top and I'm going to move this montage to this
我将把这个称为am_climb to top，然后我将把这个蒙太奇移到这个
montages folder, select move here.
montages文件夹，选择移动到这里。
Then I'm going to go back to our third person map.
然后我将回到我们的第三人称地图。
So it's inside of this third person maps, third person map.
所以它就在这个第三人称地图里面，第三人称地图。
Double click to open it.
双击来打开它。
Click save selected and we are back.
点击保存选择，我们就回来了。
So now you want to make more adjustments to that animation.
所以现在你要对这个动画做更多的调整。
You want to go back to the sequencer.
你想回到序列器中去。
So first we need to click this content folder, open this cr and the map.
所以首先我们需要点击这个内容文件夹，打开这个cr和地图。
Then go inside of this raw folder.
然后进入这个raw文件夹里面。
You can see there's another folder created and it's named after our animation sequence.
你可以看到有另一个文件夹被创建，它是以我们的动画序列命名的。
Double click to open it.
双击来打开它。
So this is the sequencer.
所以这就是序列器。
If you double click to open this, and you can see this is what we've just done.
如果你双击打开这个，你可以看到这就是我们刚刚做的。
So you can remove keys, add more keys, and if you want to sync the changes you make in
所以你可以删除钥匙，添加更多的钥匙，如果你想同步你在这里所做的改变
here, simply clicking file save all here won't work.
如果你想同步你在这里所做的改变，简单地点击文件保存这里是行不通的。
So if you like to sync all the changes, you'll need to click this button here.
所以如果你想同步所有的变化，你需要点击这里的按钮。
So you'll save the current sequence and you'll update the animation sequence that we created.
所以你将保存当前的序列，并更新我们创建的动画序列。
Alright I'm going to go back to my third person map.
好了，我要回到我的第三人称地图。
Now that we have the anim montage ready, I'm going to double click to open it.
现在我们已经准备好了动画蒙太奇，我将双击打开它。
In the next lecture, we'll look at how we can use this montage to lift our character
在下一讲中，我们将看看如何使用这个蒙太奇来提升我们的角色
up.
起来。
Later when you are doing this yourself, so same as I did, you'll need to create a new
以后当你自己做这个的时候，就像我做的一样，你需要创建一个新的
map.
地图。
Then you can go inside of the animation sequence that you want to adjust, click the drop down
然后你可以在你想调整的动画序列里面，点击下拉的
edit in sequencer.
在序列器中编辑。
After that, you should be inside of the animation mode.
之后，你应该在动画模式中。
So all you need to do is removing and adding keys to the root control.
所以你需要做的就是删除和增加根控件的按键。
This step is not as complicated as it sounds.
这一步并不像它听起来那么复杂。
After this step, you can create a linked anim sequence.
这一步之后，你可以创建一个链接的动画序列。
And don't forget to enable root motion.
而且不要忘记启用根部动作。
If you don't feel like going through this process, you can download the animation that
如果你不想经历这个过程，你可以下载我在资源下拉菜单中调整的动画。
I adjusted in the resources drop down.
我在资源下拉菜单中调整的动画。
If this is what you decide to do, make sure you drag the U asset that you downloaded to
如果你决定这样做，确保你把你下载的U资产直接拖到
the content browser directly and reassign the skeleton to it.
直接拖到内容浏览器中，并将骨架重新分配给它。
However, I still highly recommend you to go through this process yourself.
然而，我仍然强烈建议你自己去完成这个过程。
Once you are familiar with it, you can pretty much use any animation from Mixamo you like.
一旦你熟悉了它，你几乎可以使用任何你喜欢的Mixamo的动画。
Alright, it's time for you to do the same.
好了，现在是时候让你做同样的事情了。
And I'll see you in the next lecture.
我们在下一个讲座中再见。
[Music]
[音乐]